Hello again. In the last module,
大家好 又见面了 上一单元中
we built a VUI application that used a commercial implementation of speech recognition.
我们用语音识别的商业实现模型创建了 VUI 应用
Like magic, the words we speak into a voice enabled device,
就像魔法一样 我们对语音支持设备说的话
are converted into text.
居然被转成了文本
In this module, we take a closer look at how speech recognition really works.
这个单元 我们要进一步探讨语音识别的工作原理
Now, when we say speech recognition,
当我们说语音识别时
we're really talking about ASR,
实际上我们指的是 ASR
or automatic speech recognition.
也就是自动语音识别
With ASR, the goal is to simply input
ASR 旨在输出任意连续语音音频输入
any continuous audio speech and output the text equivalent.
的对应文本
We want our ASR to be speaker independent and have high accuracy.
我们希望 ASR 既不局限于特定讲话人 又能具备高准确性
Such a system has long been a core goal of AI,
长期以来 这类系统一直被视为人工智能的核心目标
and in the 1980s and 1990s,
20 世纪 80 年代和 90 年代
advances in probabilistic models began to make ASR a reality.
概率模型的突破使 ASR 逐渐成为了现实
We'll start by asking the question,
我们先来问个问题
what makes speech recognition hard?
语音识别的难点是什么？
Like many other AI problems we've seen,
就像我们看过的其它诸多人工智能问题
ASR can be implemented by gathering a large pool of labelled data,
要实现 ASR 我们可以收集大量的标签数据
training a model on that data,
用这些数据训练模型
and then deploying the trained model to accurately label new data.
然后用训练好的模型来准确预测新数据的标签
The twist is that speech is structured in time and has a lot of variability.
不同点在于 语音在时间上的结构的转变存在非常多的特征
We'll identify specific challenges we face when
我们将探讨语音识别面临的一些挑战
decoding spoken words and sentences into text.
这是把语音单词和句子解码成文本的难点
To understand how these challenges can be met,
要理解这些挑战出现的根源
we'll take a deeper dive into the sound signal itself as well as various speech models.
我们需要更深入地研究声音信号本身 以及多种语音模型
The sound signal is our data.
声音信号就是数据
We'll get into signal analysis,
我们会讲信号分析、
phonetics, and how to extract features to represent speech data.
语音学以及怎么提取特征来表示语音数据
Models in speech recognition can conceptually be
语音识别的模型从概念上可分为
divided into an acoustic model and a language model.
声学模型和语言模型
The acoustic model solves the problems of turning
声学模型解决了
sound signals into some kind of phonetic representation.
将声音信号转为某种语音表征的问题
The language model houses the domain knowledge of words,
语言模型则涉及单词、
grammar, and sentence structure for the language.
语法和句子结构等语言方面的知识
These conceptual models can be implemented with
这些概念模型可用
probabilistic models using machine learning algorithms.
概率模型以及机器学习算法来实现
Hidden Markov models have been refined with advances for ASR over a few decades now,
过去几十年来 随着 ASR 的进步 隐马尔可夫模型也得到了改进
and are considered the traditional ASR solution.
该模型被视为解决 ASR 问题的传统方法
Meanwhile, the cutting edge of ASR today is end-to-end Deep Neural Network Models.
而位于当今 ASR 研究前沿的则是端到端深度神经网络模型
We'll talk about both.
这两者我们都会讲解
When you've absorbed all that,
等你吸收了这些知识
you'll be ready to build your own ASR in the final project.
你就能在最后的项目里动手建立自己的 ASR 了
You'll be using deep learning tools you've already been introduced to,
对于在这里学到的深度学习工具 你不仅要学以致用
with a few new twists. Let's get started.
还要稍作调整 让我们开始吧